

Abrahim Gaber

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Software Engineer; professionally experienced with big-company software practices and systems including code and design reviews, continuous integration, testing and deployment. Generalist. Full-stack contributor. Experienced in Java Microservices, Distributed Systems, Linux, Python, SQL & NoSQL databases, frontend frameworks and API and backend design. Interested in web services, big data, systems design and finding creative solutions that can make the world a better and more fun place for everyone.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Location

New York, United States

CONTACT

- abrahim.gaber@gmail.com
- (646) 464-2447
- agaber.dev
- agaber
- agaber

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer / TL, Scaled Music Curation

YOUTUBE 2018 - 2023

- * Designed scalable systems for managing YouTube's vast corpus of artist and user generated music content which resulted in a 43% improvement in key music metadata metrics.
- * Team Lead (TL); defined near + long term objectives and strategies; maintained high system availability; mentorship.
- * Hands-on full-stack engineer; Polymer & TypeScript UI; Microservices; REST and RPC APIs; Spanner database design & optimization; Data Analytics and custom Dashboarding; Java Readability reviewer/mentor.

Senior Software Engineer, CorpEng & Enterprise Legal Apps

GOOGLE 2015 - 2018

- * Indexed legal documents and made them available for structured and unstructured search to Google's legal teams.
- * Created ETL (extract, transform, load) pipelines using Google Cloud Platform (GCP) and proprietary distributed systems.
- * Full stack contributions. AngularJS; AppEngine; BigQuery; Google Cloud SQL; Google Cloud PubSub; Hibernate; JavaScript; Java.

Software Engineer, Ads

OGLE 2008 - 2015

- * Designed buy-side products that enabled clients to traffic highly visible ad campaigns efficiently.
- * Built big data pipelines by leveraging Google proprietary distributed systems, NoSQL databases, Master Election and async notification systems (pub/sub).

Software Developer

MEDIDATA SOLUTIONS

2005 - 2008

- * Integrated custom functionality into base enterprise web applications that captured and reported on clinical trial data.
- * Delivered results using C#, ASP.NET and Microsoft SQL Server.

Computer Hardware Technician

4G DATA SYSTEMS 2004 - 2005

- * Repaired IBM PC compatible computer hardware, servers, laptops, and printers.
- * Certified CompTIA A+ and Network+ professional.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science

CITY UNIVERSITY OF NEW YORK - COLLEGE OF STATEN ISLAND

2004

SKILLS

Java	Pyth	Python JavaSc		pt TypeSc		C#	C++	SQL	HTML / C	css / sass
Kubernetes		gRPC	Spring Boot		MongoDB		MySQL	Google Cloud Platform (G		
Linux	Git	Merc	urial Boostrap		Do	cker	NodeJS Distributed Sy		outed Syste	ems
API Des	ign	REST	T Frontend Web Developme			nent	Backend Systems Design			PubSub
Big Data SQL and NoSQL Database Systems										